Guide to the Ira and Edita Morirs Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Manuscripts
  - Subseries III.1: Ira V. Morris
    - "The Stockholm Novel" (or "The Stockholm Saga"), novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 241)
    - "Such a Pretty Village" (or "The Stranger"), novel, complete draft [#1], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 242)
    - "Such a Pretty Village" (or "The Stranger"), novel, complete draft [#2], p.1-150, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 243)
    - "Such a Pretty Village" (or "The Stranger"), novel, complete draft [#2], p.151-262, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 244)
    - "Such a Pretty Village" (or "The Stranger"), novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, p.1-204, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 245)
    - "Such a Pretty Village" (or "The Stranger"), novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, p.205-290, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 246)
    - "Such a Pretty Village" (or "The Stranger"), novel, incomplete draft, carbon copy, p.1-180, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 247)
    - "Such a Pretty Village" (or "The Stranger"), novel, incomplete draft, carbon copy, p.181-265, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 248)
    - "Such a Pretty Village" (or "The Stranger"), novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 249)
    - "Such a Pretty Village" (or "The Stranger"), novel, corrections, 1969, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 250)
    - "Such a Pretty Village", book reviews, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 251)
    - "The Teaman", short story, published version appearing in Story, Vol. II, no. 11, Feb. 1933 (Box 15, Folder 252)
    - "Thoughts on the Coming PEN Congress", article, published version written for the Asahi Shimbun, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 253)
    - "The Tree Within", review, 18 March 1949 (Box 15, Folder 254)
    - "Trip to Geysir", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 255)
    - "Trip to Geysir", short story, incomplete draft, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 256)
    - "Twenty Years Have Passed", public letter (4 versions), 1965 (Box 15, Folder 257)
    - "Twenty Years Have Passed", public letter, fragments, [1965] (Box 15, Folder 258)
    - "Under the Mushroom Cloud", book review of Death in Life: Survivors of Hiroshima by Robert Jay Lifton, published version appearing in Saturday Review, 3 Feb. 1968 (Box 15, Folder 259)
    - "Who is Being Judged?", public letter (2 versions), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 260)
    - Miscellaneous Handwritten Notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 261)
  - Subseries III.2: Edita Morris
    Primarily drafts, typescripts, notes, fragments, and published versions of literary works by Edita Morris. Included are novels, short stories, articles, and unpublished prose. In addition, there are book reviews, adaptations, and radio program transcripts about her work. Arranged alphabetically by title, then chronologically.
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, p.1-130, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 262)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, p.131-214, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 263)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#1], p.1-130, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 264)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#1], p.131-214, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 265)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#2], p.1-120, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 266)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#2], p.121-227, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 267)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#3], p.1-115, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 268)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#3], p.116-158, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 269)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft, last version, p.1-125, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 270)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, complete draft, last version, p.126-183, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 271)
    - "A-FRI-CA", novel, notes, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 272)
    - "After the Ball", short story, published version, text in German, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 273)
    - "After the Ball", short story, published version appearing in Harper's Bazaar, Nov. 1943 (Box 16, Folder 274)
    - "Amar-to Love", short story, published version appearing in Harper's Bazaar, 15 Sept. 1941 (Box 17, Folder 275)
    - "American Summer Day 1943: Radio Talk for Sweden", radio program (2 versions), 1943 (Box 17, Folder 276)
    - "The Animals", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 277)
      [See also "Hotel Imperial", box 20, folder 349; "The Machine Gunned Rice", box 26, folder 424]
    - "The Animals", short story, published version, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 278)
    - "Aunt Ninna", short story, printed version (2 copies), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 279)
    - "Aunt Ninna", short story, published version, text in French, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 280)
    - "Auntie Ninna", short story, published version appearing in Harper's Bazaar, April 1943 (Box 17, Folder 281)
    - "Autobiographical Note", note (9 versions), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 282)
    - "Ball of Yarn", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 283)
    - "Ball of Yarn", short story, published version appearing in Selected Writing, no. 5, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 284)
    - "Biographical Note", note (5 versions), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 285)
    - "Birth of an Old Lady", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 286)
    - "A Blade of Grass", short story, complete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 287)
    - "A Blade of Grass", short story, fragments with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 288)
    - "A Blade of Grass", short story, published version appearing in Story Magazine, Aug. 1936 (Box 17, Folder 289)
    - "A Blade of Grass", copyright certificates, 1944 & 1964 (Box 17, Folder 290)
    - "Caput Mortuum", short story, published version appearing in Harper's Bazaar, June 1941 (Box 17, Folder 291)
    - "Caput Mortuum", short story, published version appearing in Le Revue de Paris, text in French, May 1962 (Box 17, Folder 292)
    - "Ce Jour-La", short story, published version, text in French, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 293)
    - "Charade", book reviews, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 294)
    - "Charade", theatrical adaptation by Mark Orrin Walker, Aug. 1960 (Box 17, Folder 295)
    - "Contemporary Authors Revision", note, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 296)
    - "Da Bomben Faldt", article, published version, text in Danish, 7 Aug. 1970 (Box 17, Folder 297)
    - "Dear Me, and Other Tales from My Native Sweden", collection of short stories, complete draft, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 298)
    - "Dear Me, and Other Tales from My Native Sweden", collection of short stories, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 299)
    - "Dear Me, and Other Tales from My Native Sweden", collection of short stories, incomplete draft, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 300)
    - "Dear Me, and Other Tales from My Native Sweden", collection of short stories, fragments, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 301)
    - "Dear Me, and Other Tales from My Native Sweden", collection of short stories, proof, [1967] (Box 18, Folder 302)
    - "Dear Me, and Other Tales from My Native Sweden", blurb (2 versions), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 303)
    - "Dear Me, and Other Tales from My Native Sweden", book reviews, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 304)
    - "Dress Rehearsal", short story, published version appearing in Mademoiselle, April 1943 (Box 18, Folder 305)
    - "Echo in Asia", blurb (3 versions), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 306)
    - "Echo in Asia", book reviews, 1958-1962 (Box 18, Folder 307)
    - "Echo in Asia", radio program, text in German, 27 Dec. 1965 (Box 18, Folder 308)
    - "Epilogue", short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 309)
    - "Epilogue", short story, complete draft (2 versions), Sept. 1973 (Box 18, Folder 310)
    - "Epilogue", short story, complete draft, final copy, Sept. 1973 (Box 18, Folder 311)
    - "Faith", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 312)
    - "First Radio Talk to Sweden", radio program, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 313)
    - "Frog on a Pat of Butter", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 314)
    - "The Gateway to India", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 315)
    - "The Gateway to India", short story, published version appearing in Eastern Horizon, Dec. 1961 (Box 18, Folder 316)
    - "A Goldfish in Detroit", short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 317)
    - "A Goldfish in Detroit", short story, published version (2 versions), text in German, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 318)
    - "Golfball", short story, handwritten complete draft, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 319)
    - "Greek Tragedy in Nineteen Acts", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 320)
      [See also "Stars on Your Forehead", box 33, folder 500-502 and box 34, folder 503; and "Toil and the Deed", box 35, folder 529 and box 36, folder 530-533]
    - "Greek Tragedy in Seven Acts", short story, complete draft with factual background, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 321)
    - "Greek Tragedy in Seven Acts", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 322)
    - "Greek Tragedy in Seven Acts", short story, complete draft, final version, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 323)
    - "Greek Tragedy in Seven Acts", short story, incomplete draft, text in French, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 324)
    - "Greek Tragedy in Seven Acts", short story, fragments, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 325)
    - "Griechische Tragödie", article, published version appearing in Das Magazin, text in German, Feb. 1968 (Box 19, Folder 326)
    - "Guerrillero with a Flower Between His Lips", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 327)
    - "Guerrillero with a Flower Between His Lips", short story, fragments, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 328)
    - "Guerrillero with a Flower Between His Lips", short story, published version, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 329)
    - "A Happy Day" (or "Sand"), novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 330)
    - "A Happy Day" (or "Sand"), novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 331)
    - "A Happy Day" (or "Sand"), novel, incomplete draft, carbon copy, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 332)
    - "A Happy Day" (or "Sand"), novel, final version, carbon copy, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 333)
    - "A Happy Day" (or "Sand"), novel, proof with handwritten corrections, text in Swedish, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 334)
    - "A Happy Day" (or "Sand"), novel, complete draft, photocopy, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 335)
    - "A Happy Day" (or "Sand"), novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 336)
    - "A Happy Day", book reviews, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 337)
    - "He Went Mad with Guilt", book review of Dark Star: Hiroshima Reconsidered in the Life of Claude Eatherly of Lincoln Park, Texas, by Ronnie Dugger, published version appearing in SR, 2 March 1968 (Box 20, Folder 338)
    - "Heart of Marzipan", short story, published version appearing in Mademoiselle, Oct. 1943 (Box 20, Folder 339)
    - "Hiroshima", article, published version appearing in Die Weltfühne, text in German, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 340)
    - "Hiroshima", speech (4 versions), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 341)
    - "Hiroshima City of Ghosts", article, printed version, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 342)
    - "The Hiroshima Man", article, complete draft (2 versions), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 343)
    - "Hiroshima Man", article, published version appearing in Kvinner, text in Norwegian, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 344)
    - "Hiroshima Man", article, published version appearing in vi Kvinner, text in Swedish, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 345)
    - "Hiroshima Man", article, published version appearing in The Mennonite, 25 May 1965 (Box 20, Folder 346)
    - "Hiroshimas Skörd", article, incomplete published version, text in Swedish, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 347)
    - "Horse with Hoof of Fire", short story, published version appearing in The New Mexico Quarterly Review, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 348)
    - "Hotel Imperial", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 349)
      [See also "The Animals", box 17, folder 277-278; "The Machine Gunned Rice", box 26, folder 424]
    - "How Keeping, Hope Fine", novel, complete draft, old original, carbon copy, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 350)
    - "How Keeping, Hope Fine", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, old copy, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 351)
    - "How Keeping, Hope Fine", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 352)
    - "How Keeping, Hope Fine", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, working copy, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 353)
    - "How Keeping, Hope Fine", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, new version, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 354)
    - "How Keeping, Hope Fine", novel, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 355)
    - "How Keeping, Hope Fine", novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 356)
    - "How Keeping, Hope Fine", novel, publication contract for French version, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 357)
    - "How Keeping, Hope Fine", book reviews, 1975-1978 (Box 21, Folder 358)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections [#1], n.d. (Box 21, Folder 359)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections [#2], n.d. (Box 21, Folder 360)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Apricot Trees" (or "The Stew"), short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 361)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Beauty", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 362)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Chinese Tools" (or "Tools"), short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 363)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Dirty Gerty", short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 364)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Fascism über Alles" (or "More of the Same"), short story, complete draft (5 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 365)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Français et Françaises", short story, complete draft (2 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 366)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Freaks", short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 367)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Genius", short story, complete draft (6 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 368)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "A Great Swede, A Great Jew", short story, complete draft (2 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 369)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Home", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 370)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "I Never Get a Chance to Take a Chance", short story, complete draft (5 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 371)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "If the Sun Could Doubt", short story, complete draft (3 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 372)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Ja Vi Elsker Dette Landet", short story, complete draft (3 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 373)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Joie de Vivre", short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 374)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Kiss", short story, complete draft (7 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 375)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Life Has Treated Me Well", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 376)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Love in Lappland", short story, complete draft (2 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 377)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Lucky India", short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 378)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Mothers of the World Unite", short story, complete draft (3 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 379)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Nearer My God to Thee" (or "Faith"), short story, complete draft (6 versions), n.d. (Box 22, Folder 380)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Revolution", short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 23, Folder 381)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories: "Snooky", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 382)
    - "If the Sun Could Doubt", collection of short stories, fragments, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 383)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories, complete draft, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 384)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 385)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories: "Croissants", short story, complete draft (3 versions), n.d. (Box 23, Folder 386)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories: "Five Terrible Women", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 387)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories: "Français et Françaises", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 388)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories: "Genius", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 389)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories: "A Great Swede, A Great Jew", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 390)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories: "Ja, Vi Elsker Dette Landet", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 391)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories: "The Stew", short story, complete draft (3 versions), n.d. (Box 23, Folder 392)
    - "Insights", collection of short stories, fragments, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 393)
    - "It's a Women's World", book reviews, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 394)
    - "Karriär", book reviews, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 395)
    - "Kauko", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 396)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, carbon copy, p.1-115, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 397)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, carbon copy, p.116-235, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 398)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, carbon copy, p.236-319, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 399)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#1], p.1-150, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 400)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#1], p.151-314, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 401)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#2], p.1-110, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 402)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#2], p.111-239, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 403)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#3], p.1-120, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 404)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#3], p.121-240, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 405)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, complete draft, photocopy [#3], p.241-297, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 406)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, incomplete draft, photocopy, p.6-150, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 407)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, incomplete draft, photocopy, p.151-300, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 408)
    - "Kill a Beggar", novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 409)
    - "Kullan", copyright certificates, 1944 & 1966 (Box 25, Folder 410)
    - "Let's Remember Together", short story, published version appearing in Good Housekeeping, May 1944 (Box 25, Folder 411)
    - "Life, Wonderful Life", novel, complete draft, p.1-124, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 412)
    - "Life, Wonderful Life", novel, complete draft, p.125-195, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 413)
    - "Life, Wonderful Life", novel, proof with handwritten corrections, p.1-136, [1971] (Box 25, Folder 414)
    - "Life, Wonderful Life", novel, proof with handwritten corrections, p.137-192, [1971] (Box 26, Folder 415)
    - "Life, Wonderful Life", novel, fragments, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 416)
    - "Life, Wonderful Life", novel, cover designs, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 417)
    - "Life, Wonderful Life", novel, publisher's note (5 versions), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 418)
    - "Life, Wonderful Life", book reviews, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 419)
    - "Lili Died in April", short story, published version appearing in Lovat Dickson's Magazine, Vol.3, no. 6, Dec. 1934 (Box 26, Folder 420)
    - "Love to Vietnam", novel, fragments, text in German, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 421)
    - "Love to Vietnam", book reviews, 1968-1970 (Box 26, Folder 422)
    - "Love to Vietnam", publicity, text in French, Sept. 1969 (Box 26, Folder 423)
    - "The Machine-Gunned Rice", short story, published version, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 424)
      [See also "The Animals", box 17, folder 277-278; "Hotel Imperial", box 20, folder 349]
    - "The Melody", short story, incomplete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 425)
    - "The Melody", short story, published version appearing in Mademoiselle, Feb. 1945 (Box 26, Folder 426)
    - "The Melody", copyright certificate, March 1945 (Box 26, Folder 427)
    - "The Melody", screenplay adaptation by Tony Barr, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 428)
    - "Mono", short story, complete draft with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 429)
    - "Mono", short story, fragments, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 430)
    - "Mothers of the World Unite", essay, complete draft (2 versions), 6 Aug. 1981 (Box 26, Folder 431)
    - "My Darling from the Lions", novel, book jacket, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 432)
    - "My Darling from the Lions", radio programs, 1943 (Box 27, Folder 433)
    - "My Darling from the Lions", book reviews, 1943-1951 (Box 27, Folder 434)
    - "My Darling from the Lions", novel, incomplete printed copy, text in Swedish, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 435)
    - "Nature's Child", short story, published version appearing in The Reader's Digest, Sept. 1944 (Box 27, Folder 436)
      [See also "The Pagan", box 27, folder 441-442]
    - "Nature's Child", short story, published version appearing in Det Bästa, text in Swedish, Dec. 1944 (Box 27, Folder 437)
    - "The One Who Loved Me", short story, complete draft (4 versions), n.d. (Box 27, Folder 438)
    - "The One Who Loved Me", short story, fragments, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 439)
    - "The Open Mouth", short story, published version appearing in Harper's Bazaar, July 1943 (Box 27, Folder 440)
    - "The Pagan", short story, printed version, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 441)
      [See also "Nature's Child", box 27, folder 436-437]
    - "The Pagan", short story, published version appearing in Harper's Bazaar, July 1944 (Box 27, Folder 442)
    - "A Pair of Fine Wings", short story, complete draft, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 443)
    - "A Pair of Fine Wings", short story, published version, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 444)
    - "A Pair of White Gloves", novel, complete draft, softbound, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 445)
    - "A Pair of White Gloves", novel, complete draft with handwritten corrections, softbound, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 446)
    - "A Pair of White Gloves", novel, revised copy, p.1-147, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 447)
    - "A Pair of White Gloves", novel, revised copy, p.148-255, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 448)
    - "Radio Talk to Sweden", radio program, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 449)
    - "Le Rideau de Peluche Rouge", short story, published version appearing in Le Revue de Paris, text in French, Nov. 1966 (Box 28, Folder 450)
    - "Schools in Sweden and in the United States", essay, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 451)
    - "Secret", short story, complete draft (2 versions), n.d. (Box 28, Folder 452)
    - "The Seeds of Hiroshima", novel, complete draft, softbound [#1], n.d. (Box 28, Folder 453)
    - "The Seeds of Hiroshima", novel, complete draft, softbound [#2], n.d. (Box 28, Folder 454)
    - "The Seeds of Hiroshima", novel, complete draft, softbound [#3], n.d. (Box 28, Folder 455)
    - "The Seeds of Hiroshima", novel, fragment, text in French, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 456)
    - "The Seeds of Hiroshima", lists to be sent copies, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 457)